In this example, we're starting with two data sets,
在这个案例中 我们开始使用两个数据集
customer data from 2010 and customer data from 2011.
2010 年的客户数据和 2011 年的客户数据
And we want to create one data set with all of the customers for
我们想要创建一个同时包括
both 2010 and 2011.
2010 年和 2011 年客户数据的数据集
However, you don't always get data sets in the exact same format.
但是 你不会总能得到格式完全一样的数据集
Sometimes they have different field names, and
有时它们有不同的字段名
sometimes they have extra fields that don't exist in all the data sets.
有时它们有一样的字段名但是不是出现在所有的数据集中
Notice that in the first data set, we have the fields ID and Name.
注意看第一个数据集 有字段 ID 和字段 Name
Yet the second data set has a different name field called Full Name, and
然而第二个数据集有一个不同命名的字段 Full Name
an additional field called Phone.
和一个额外的字段 Phone
We're going to union these data sets together,
我们准备把数据集的字段用行的连接合并到一起
even though they have different field names and
即使它们在同一个字段有不同的字段名
an extra field, that are not common to both data sets.
即使这不是两个完全相同的数据集
To do this, we simply drag in the Union tool, bringing it close to the customer
要做到这一点 我们先简单地拖拽 Union 工具 把它放到
data 2010 data set so that it attaches to this data set first.
Customer data 2010 数据集的旁边 使得它和这个数据集建立联系
Then we manually draw a connection from customer data 2011 data set
然后我们手动绘制从 customer data 2011 数据集到
to the Union tool.
Union 工具的联系
The Union tool can have unlimited inputs into it.
Union 工具对于向工具里输入不限制数量
So you can union more than just two data sets.
因此行的连接你可以连接超过两个数据集
Now we can configure the tool.
现在我们可以设置工具了
Coming to the Configuration area on the left,
来到左边的 Configuration (设置) 区域
it says Auto Configure by Name up at the top.
在顶部显示 Auto Configure by Name (按照名称自动设置)
This is the default way of configuring the Union tool.
这是在 Union 工具中默认的设置方式
When we run the work flow and we look at the output,
当我们点击 run the work flow (运行工作流程) 的时候我们可以看到输出
we can see that the data in the ID field is lined up.
我们可以看到在 ID 字段的数据被有序排列
But the data in the name field is not,
但是在 name 字段的数据没有被有序排列
as there are both Name and Full Name fields containing name information.
因为同时有字段 Name 和字段 Full Name 包含姓名信息
To get the fields to line up better, we choose Manually Configure Fields.
想要使字段被排列得更好 我们选择 Manually Configure Fields (人工设置字段)
Then we click on Full Name, we click on the arrow moving it to the left so
接着我们点击 Full Name 我们点击箭头把它移动到左边
that it's now lined up with the Name field.
这样 现在它和字段 Name 一起排列
And then to remove the gap between these two fields, we select Phone and
然后 移除两个字段中间的空格 我们选择 Phone
click on the left arrow again to move that field over.
再次点击左箭头 移动这个字段
[SOUND] When we run the work flow, you can see all of the names in the Name
当我们点击run the work flow 你可以看到在 Name 字段的所有名字
field now, and all the fields lined up as expected.
所有的字段按照要求有序排列